# VAIRAVAN U

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vairavan-u-270b4563/https://github.com/vairavan6

vairavan.u@gmail.com (+91) 90424-03354

(+91) 9087463405

## **Profile:**

4.5+ years of Experience with architecting and developing large-scale Javascript and Java applications for Japanbasedinternational company, competing in the field of ERP. Specialties include desktop app development, full-stack Web development in Javascript & Java technologies, Node -Javascript apps with high scalability. Greatest strength is business awareness & striving to leverage my IT skills with enthusiasm.

#### **Education:**

# • B.E ECE -8.55cgpa

Anna University Aff. (Saranathan College of Eng., Trichy). Year 2015.

• High School -92.25%

BHEL Matric HSC School. Year 2011.

• SSLC -91%

ARK HSC School. Year 2009

#### **Technical Skills:**

Design: HTML, CSS.

Programming Languages: JavaScript / ECMA Script, JAVA, XML.

Desktop App: Maven, JavaFx

WebFrameworks/Libraries:

FrontEnd: React.js, Redux, Webpack, Gulp.js, Babel, Eslint, Ace.

JS Backend: Node Environment, Express, Nest.js, StrongLoop.

Java Backend: Maven, SpringBoot, Hibernate, ORM-data jpa.

Database: SQL-PostgresSql / NoSQL-MongoDB.

SRE: Docker, Ansible, AWS.

Servers: ApacheTomcat, Nginx {Loadbalancer & Server}.

Caching: Redis.
Version Control System: Git, SVN.

Others: Jenkins, Redmine/Jitamin, Agile/SCRUM.

Tools:

Software/IDE: Terminal, Microsoft Office, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse.

Operating Systems: Linux, Microsoft Windows.

Progressing Stack: Vert.x, React-Native, mobile ui frameworks, Typescript.

# **Personal Projects:**

## 1. "For You - Mr. ServiceMan" Social Networking App:

An application developed with a major concern for society. Started with a 2 enthusiasts and now elaborated to a team of 10 members. The application majorly concentrates on connecting people who has the heart to donate to needy, but time constraints restrict them. So we had a brainstorm session and came up with an idea, that a person who wish to donate just make a mark in the application.

Volunteers from government approved NGO's can collect the things {from small pin to everything.} and make sure it reaches needy.

https://github.com/ForYou-Always/forYou

The application is currently in development. As it has larger scope & wide range of features.

**Stack:** React + Node + Express + Mongodb.

# 2. "ForYou - Mr.Examiner" Online Interview/Exam Conducting App:

An application to conduct the exams, which is self maintained. Consists of three tier architecture. SuperAdmin, Manager, Candidate. Super admin has levels of accessibility to prepare questions & questionnare, managers. Managers can multiple questionnares to candidates. And candidates are allowed to take up multipletests with lots of features. Now the 342 application has been developed and completely for US client as freelancing project.

http://www.vexamine.com/home.html

**Stack:** React + Springboot + PostgreSql.

# 3. "Freelancing: Common Intelligence - US Marine Corps Project"

An application to get the anonymous intelligence information from the common citizens. So there will be a fool-proof and fearless mechanism for commoners to give the spy-info to intelligence agencies with a secret identity.

This application can also be used by commoners to make anonymous transaction among themselves. Stripe is used for transactions. Was the lead API developer in this project.

**Stack:** NodeJS – Nest.js & StrongLoop frameworks, Stripe Payment platform integration.

#### 4. "For You - Mr. Mechanic" Automobile Service Mobile app:

Started to prepare a sketch for connecting nearby mechanic to customers whose vehicle got breakdown in the middle. It has kick started and in analysis phase lots of ground work is going on for feature upgrades and efficient design. Planned to go with ReactNative & Node.

**Stack:** React-Native + Node.

#### 4. "ForYou - Versatile":

Several projects are on the run in field work & study phase. Regarding market trend and competitors. Includes FoodVendor Managment, School Management, Hospital Management. Internal team has been deployed for the research and development.

Stack: React, React-Native, Node, SpringBoot, PostgreSql, Mongodb.

# **Work Experience:**

#### IVTL INFOVIEW TECHNOLOGIES Pvt Ltd

Chennai — Research & Dev Team Lead (ERP-Accounts)

#### January 2019 - Present {R&D Team Lead}

- Started as Team lead. After facing lot of issues in product development got a spark and Started to develop Tools to speed the product development in turn, Development improved their speed with the tools, which has drastically reduced lot of man-hours.
- After shown a POC, now Moved to R&D as a Technical Lead. The specifications for the tool will be self driven. Involves lot of ground work to get to know the issues faced by developers.
- After the successful reach of tool started to get requirements & specs from Overseas (JAPAN).
- Transformed from internal tool to a Wide Scope Product which is currently used by team of more than 400+developers40+Team leads and managers. During the several phases of Development & Operation.
- Total product from the scratch i.e Design to Deployment and service maintenance.

Architecture: React + Node + Express + MongoDb + Springboot + Nginx.

Chennai — Lead Software Developer (ERP)

#### October 2016 - December 2018 { Technical Team Lead }

- Oversaw a team of Engineers in the development of full stackapplication which will be utilized by developers forcontrolling cloud resources.
- Utilizing technologies SpringBoot-React. Cut the cost by developing a Ansible Script Execution Platform in React-JS.

Chennai — Full Stack Development Engineer (ERP-HR)

#### June 2015 - August 2016 {Developer}

- Over a period of one year developed around 10 full stack application in the ERP like, accounts finance, hr, payroll, Supply chain management.
- In the Mid appointed as a Group Lead managing a small team of freshers & co-developers, trained them to achieve the highly scalable ERP Web Application.

#### **INTERESTS & HOBBIES:**

- Traditional Martial Arts. Human Psychology.
- Passion in researching the the hidden & lost form of ancient arts & principles.

### Languages Known:

- Tamil Expert
- English Proficient